MUHAMMAD RAKIBUL HASAN

Phouse#28, Road#4, Block#A, Banashree,, Rampura, Dhaka

+8801726859915

akibul.hasan58@gmail.com



Career Objective:

Seeking for a better opportunity to establish myself as a well-qualified Electrical Engineer (MEP) contributing my knowledge and experiences that I have gained through extensive studies and practical electrical design.

Career Summary:

I am a skilled electrical engineer with a degree in the field and a decade of experience in the area of electrical engineering. I am trained in the area of electrical systems and have concentrated knowledge of the implementation process as well. I have experience leading teams and working collaboratively with others in fast-paced environments. My analytic abilities, strong interpersonal skills, and reliable nature make me an asset to many teams. Drawing Design is my passion.

Special Qualification:

Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, and possess a wide range of technical skills.

Highly dedicated and reliable personality with excellent project management abilities.

Enjoys being part of a team.

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 10.4 yrs

1. BIM Engineer Electrical (2.1 yrs)

(17 Apr 2022 - Continuing)

Surbana Jurong Bangladesh

Area of Expertise:

BIM Modeling, Electrical Designing

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Developing BIM Models of Lighting, Electrical system, and Power distribution other areas of electrical construction Manage and Coordinate project deliveries.
- Assist Senior Engineer in producing details/drawings that comply with design criteria, and contract requirements.
- Assist Senior BIM Coordinator in coordinating mechanical/plumbing models with other disciplines through Navisworks.
 - Design complete Electrical system, Cable schedules, Breaker size design, preparing SLD (Single Line Diagram) as per load requirement of the project.
 - Light fixture design, Power schedule, Load calculation, Cable tray design, Earthing design, Trunking and Conduit design, Lighting protection system

design, ELV system design.

- Site supervision, helping the site engineers to understand the drawing design and preparing BOQ based on that. Instructing them to do the work as per approved drawing design.
- Learn and Demonstrate proficiency in software related to BIM.

2. JR. ELECTRICAL ENGINEER (3.1 yrs)

(1 Apr 2021 – 14 Apr 2022)

DESIGN DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANTS LTD.

Area of Expertise:

CAD, Consultant, Electrical Desigining

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Working with NKDOS Consortium, Detail Design & Tender Assistance for Dhaka Rapid Transit Development Project (Line-1) Depot.
- Preparing conceptual as it is working design with sectional views by AutoCAD as following the international standard.
- Design complete electrical system, cable schedules, breaker size design, preparing SLD (Single Line Diagram) as per load requirement of the project.
- Light fixture design, Power schedule, Load calculation, Cable tray design, Earthing design, Trunking and Conduit design, Lighting protection system design.
- Site supervision, helping the site engineers to understand the drawing design and preparing BOQ based on that. Instructing them to do the work as per approved drawing design.
- Communicate with vendors.

3. ASSISTANT ENGINEER (ELECTRICAL) (1.1 yrs)

(1 Mar 2020 - 31 Mar 2021)

EZZY AUTOMATIONS LTD.

Area of Expertise:

CAD, Electrical Desigining, Supervision

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Worked under ITD (ITALIAN THAI DEVELOPMENT LTD.) as a sub-contractor, one of the biggest projects of our country Dhaka Mass Rapid Transit Project (MRT Line-6 CP-3&4) in the MEP Team.
- Electromechanical drawing preparing for MRT Line-6.
- Preparing working design with sectional views by AutoCAD as following the international standard. GA drawings for equipment.
- Design complete electrical system, cable schedules, breaker size design, preparing SLD (Single Line Diagram) as per load requirement of the project.
- Light fixture design, Power schedule, Load calculation, Cable tray design, Earthing design, Trunking and Conduit design, Lighting protection system design.
- Site supervision, helping the site engineers to understand the drawing design and preparing BOQ based on that. Instructing them to do the work as per approved drawing design.

4. QUALITY ASSURANCE OFFICER (1.8 yrs)

(1 May 2018 - 28 Feb 2020)

DESIGN DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANTS LTD.

Area of Expertise:

Document Controller, Document Processing, QUALITY ASSURANCE

Duties/Responsibilities:

As I always cherish doing any kind of work and accepting any challenges, I have joined here in the ICT department as a Quality Assurance Officer. This is a great challenge to myself working out of my comfort zone. This is a government project, working under The Ministry of Commerce, Register and Joint Stock Companies of Bangladesh, project name "Digitization of RJSC Historical Records and Documents."

- Document checking, have to maintain working quality, document archiving, checking the scan quality, operating MIS, preparing all the reports.
- Leading individual technical teamwork.
- Supervise the whole process of work also planning.
- With desk work, perform various duties as assigned.

5. MAINTENANCE ENGINEER (2 yrs)

(1 May 2016 - 30 Apr 2018)

SEACOTEX GROUP LTD.

Area of Expertise:

Maintainance, Payroll management, System support

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Supervise all the electrical maintenance works of the factory.
- Leading individual technical teamwork, guiding them also training up the team as per required.
- Doing the IT-related works of the factory, maintaining payroll system with HRD software.
- With desk work, perform various duties as assigned.

6. ASSISTANT ENGINEER (2.5 yrs)

(1 Feb 2011 - 31 Jul 2013)

CONCRETE & STEEL TECHNOLOGIES LTD.

Area of Expertise:

Commissioning Maintenance, Office assisting, Supervision

Duties/Responsibilities:

- BTS Commissioning & Installation, End-to-end telecommunication expertise.
- Mobile system expansion, Operation, and Maintenance.
- Site Supervision.
- Warehousing materials with logistic support.
- Leading individual technical teamwork, guiding them also training up the team as per required.

• Prepared electrical detail drawing for construction and implementation using AutoCAD.

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pas.Year
Bachelor of Science (B.Sc)	Electrical & Electronic Engineering	Stamford University Bangladesh	CGPA: 2.69 out of 4	2015
Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)	Science	Ideal Collage	CGPA: 3.75 out of 5	2005
Secondary School Certificate (SSC)	Science	Segunbagicha High School	CGPA: 3.75 out of 5	2003

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Transformer	Transformer Manufacturing	EnergyPac Bangladesh	Bangladesh	Gazipur	2010	30 Day

Career and Application Information:

: Mid Level Job Looking For Available For : Full Time Present Salary : Tk. 55000 BDT : Tk. 80000 BDT **Expected Salary**

Engineer/BIM/Telecommunication, Production/Operation, CAD Operator, Other : Special Skilled Jobs Preferred Job Category

Preferred District : Dhaka

Preferred Country : Australia, Canada, Germany, Japan, UAE

Preferred Organization Types : Engineering Firms, Consulting Firms, Telecommunication, Group of Companies

Skill:

Fields of Skill

- AutoCAD
- Revit
- Dialux
- Navisworks
- MS Office (Word, Excel)
- **Electrical Engineering**
- Electrical Design
- BIM

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
English	Professional	Professional	Professional

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Hasan Ali Mother's Name : Rawshanara Hasan Date of Birth : 3'rd Jan, 1989

Gender : Male

Passport No : BQ0214815
Passport Issue Date : 9/9/2017
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshi
Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : House#28, Road#4, Block#A, Banashree,, Rampura, Dhaka

Current Location : Dhaka Blood Group : AB+

Reference (s):

Reference: 01

Name : SHAH ALAM

Organization : DEVELOPMENT DESIGN CONSULTANTS LTD.

Designation : Senior Architect

Address : Mohakhali, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Primary Mobile No : +8801712819780

Primary Email : shahalam.alam5@gmail.com

Relation : Professional

Reference: 02

MD. ABUL HOSSAIN

DEVELOPMENT DESIGN

CONSULTANTS LTD.

Senior Engineer (Mechanical)

Mohakhali, Dhaka, Bangladesh

+8801716505359

abulhossain.hossain@yahoo.com

Professional